Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and it's the holiday season.
我是Catherine，现在是节日季。
That's right.
没错。
It's almost Christmas and so we are bringing you one of the most typical Christmas songs
快到圣诞节了，所以我们为大家带来一首最经典的圣诞歌曲，
or Christmas carols I guess in all over the world probably.
或者说圣诞颂歌，我想全世界可能都这样。
That's right and I've heard it in many different languages, even Chinese.
没错，我听过很多不同语言的版本，甚至还有中文的。
Yeah, even Chinese.
是啊，甚至还有中文的。
Ding dong dang.
叮咚当。
Okay, I'll have to ask.
好吧，我得问问。
Yeah, you have to ask.
是啊，你得问问。
But yeah, we're talking about Jingle Bells today.
不过，我们今天要讲的是《铃儿响叮当》。
So the famous song Jingle Bells, you'll hear it everywhere, especially during the Christmas
这首著名的歌曲《铃儿响叮当》，你到处都能听到，尤其是在圣诞节
season, only during the Christmas season.
期间，只在圣诞节期间。
And so let's listen to the song.
那么，我们来听听这首歌。
The song is pretty long.
这首歌挺长的。
It has like a couple of different verses.
它有好几段不同的歌词。
But we've taken the main one, the first one, and the chorus, which are like the most famous
但我们选了最主要的一段，第一段，还有副歌，这些是最著名的
ones.
部分。
And so let's listen to the song.
那么，我们来听听这首歌。
This is going to be stuck in my head all day, Marco.
这首歌会在我脑子里转一整天，Marco。
I know.
我知道。
It's kind of catchy though.
不过它还挺上口的。
How can you not get into the spirit with this song?
听了这首歌，你怎么可能不融入节日气氛呢？
Well, as you said, a carol, a Christmas carol is a song and they're meant to be catchy.
嗯，就像你说的，一首颂歌，一首圣诞颂歌就是一首歌，它们就是要朗朗上口。
You get them in your head and they stay there forever.
它们会钻进你的脑子里，然后永远待在那儿。
I think it's also because every mall or shopping center you go to, they're playing these songs.
我觉得也是因为你去每个商场或购物中心，他们都在放这些歌。
So they just kind of get stuck in your head.
所以它们就自然而然地卡在你脑子里了。
In the background all the time.
一直在背景里播放。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
It makes you want to shop more.
它让你想多买东西。
Or kill someone.
或者想杀人。
Alright, so there were probably a couple of different words that you didn't understand
好了，可能这里有几个词你没听懂，
here.
我们接下来会一点一点地过一遍整首歌，并解释一下。
So we're going to go through the whole song little by little and we'll explain it.
所以从第一行开始，它说：dashing through the snow。
So starting out with the first line, it says, dashing through the snow.
嗯，好吧。
Well, okay.
这挺有意思的，因为在体育运动中，有一个项目叫100米短跑。
This is interesting because in sports, there's an event called a 100 meter dash.
嗯，所以dash就是非常快速的奔跑。
Okay, so a dash is a very quick run.
非常快，对吧？
Very fast, right?
没错。
That's right.
所以dashing through the snow就是你在雪地里快速奔跑或穿行。
So dashing through the snow is you're kind of running or going through the snow very
对，我们不知道是谁在雪地里跑，但我们知道有东西或有人在雪地里快速移动。
quickly.
Right, we don't know who is running through the snow but we know something or someone
对，我们不知道是谁在雪地里跑，但我们知道有东西或有人在雪地里快速移动。
is going very quickly through the snow.
And in the second line it says, in a one horse open sleigh.
第二行说：in a one horse open sleigh。
Okay, so now we know who's dashing through the snow.
好了，现在我们知道是谁在雪地里飞奔了。
It's a horse.
是一匹马。
It's a horse and you're in a sleigh.
是一匹马，你坐在雪橇里。
Okay, so an open sleigh means that there's no roof.
嗯，open sleigh意思是雪橇没有顶棚。
So you're sitting under the stars and there's a horse pulling your sleigh through the snow.
所以你坐在星空下，有一匹马拉着你的雪橇穿过雪地。
Okay, so a sleigh is kind of like a vehicle for the snow, right?
嗯，所以sleigh是一种在雪地上行驶的交通工具，对吧？
There's no wheels.
没有轮子。
Okay, because it's hard to drive in snow and so this is an old kind of vehicle that has
嗯，因为在雪地里开车很难，所以这是一种老式交通工具，底部可能是木头或金属，让它能滑行。
maybe wood or metal underneath to make it slide.
让它能滑行，非常好。
To make it slide, very good.
Alright and then we have this strange word here.
好了，然后我们有一个奇怪的词。
It's o apostrophe er, or, or the field we go.
是o apostrophe er，或者，或者the field we go。
Or the field we go.
或者the field we go。
Well, this is very, very common in poetry.
嗯，这在诗歌里非常非常常见。
Okay.
嗯。
So this is a way to make the word over shorter because over, you can hear it, two syllables,
所以这是一种把over这个词缩短的方式，因为over，你能听到，两个音节，over。
over.
但有时我们只想要一个音节。
But sometimes we only want one.
所以我们就说or。
So we say or.
嗯，or the fields we go。
Okay, or the fields we go.
就是over。
It's over.
嗯，有意思。
Okay, interesting.
Laughing all the way.
Laughing all the way。
Bells on bobtails ring.
Bells on bobtails ring。
Now what are bobtails?
现在，什么是bobtails？
What are these bells on bobtails?
这些bells on bobtails是什么？
Okay, well bobtails are the tails of certain animals, okay?
嗯，bobtails是某些动物的尾巴，好吗？
So we could say we have a bunny rabbit with a bobtail.
所以我们可以说有一只兔子有bobtail。
That means the tail sticks up.
意思是尾巴竖起来。
But it's also maybe reindeer have bobtails because their tails stick up.
但也许驯鹿也有bobtails，因为它们的尾巴也竖起来。
You can see them.
你能看到它们。
Okay, so I guess in this case, because it's Christmas, these animals like reindeer and
嗯，所以我想在这种情况下，因为是圣诞节，这些动物比如驯鹿和
rabbits have little bells on them.
兔子身上都挂着铃铛。
And according to the next line, making spirits bright, right?
根据下一行，making spirits bright，对吧？
So you're making people happy.
所以你在让人们开心。
That's right.
没错。
Spirit is your, your attitude or your soul.
Spirit是你的态度或灵魂。
And in this case, you're being made happy.
在这种情况下，你被弄得开心了。
You're happy because it's Christmas.
你开心是因为是圣诞节。
You're outside.
你在外面。
Very good.
非常好。
And well, he says, what fun it is to laugh and sing a slaying song tonight.
然后他说：what fun it is to laugh and sing a slaying song tonight。
Now slaying, we know that slay is this vehicle to go through the snow.
现在slaying，我们知道slay是这种在雪地里行驶的交通工具。
But a slaying song, I guess is.
但a slaying song，我想是……
Is the song we sing when we're in a slay.
是我们在雪橇上唱的歌。
So this isn't a real word, but this is something that makes the song kind of makes you think
所以这不是一个真正的词，但这是让这首歌让你觉得这些人只是在唱一首在雪橇上的特别歌曲。
that these people are just singing a special song for being in a slay.
All right.
好了。
Let's go to the chorus, jingle bells, jingle bells.
我们来看副歌：jingle bells, jingle bells。
So this word jingle, it's a verb, right?
所以这个词jingle，它是一个动词，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
To jingle, we can do it with your keys too.
To jingle，我们也可以用钥匙来做。
To jingle is to make noise when metal is touching metal.
To jingle就是金属碰金属时发出声音。
So we have bells and they ding ding ding ding ding.
所以我们有铃铛，它们叮叮叮叮叮。
They hit each other.
它们互相碰撞。
I got some keys here.
我这里有些钥匙。
I'll show you what jingling is.
我给你们演示一下什么是jingle。
So we go like this.
所以我们这样做。
Oh, jingle.
哦，jingle。
To jingle your keys, right?
To jingle your keys，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
So you can use it with keys, with bells.
所以你可以用它来形容钥匙、铃铛。
Can you use it with anything else?
还能用它来形容别的东西吗？
Anything that makes it sound like that?
任何能发出那种声音的东西？
Chimes, jingle.
风铃，jingle。
Okay, chimes, jingle.
嗯，风铃，jingle。
All right, very good.
好了，非常好。
So jingle all the way.
所以jingle all the way。
Oh, what fun it is to ride again in a one horse open sleigh.
Oh, what fun it is to ride again in a one horse open sleigh。
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all the way.
Jingle bells, jingle bells, jingle all the way。
So all the way, maybe we're going someplace.
所以all the way，也许我们在去某个地方。
All the way, wherever you're going, right?
All the way，无论你去哪里，对吧？
Home or to dinner.
回家或去吃饭。
And oh, what fun it is to ride in a one horse open sleigh.
哦，坐在一匹马拉的敞篷雪橇上多么有趣啊。
So the chorus is not very hard and neither is the first verse, but you know, sometimes
所以副歌部分不难，第一段也不难，但你知道，有时候
the song is pretty fast, so sometimes you don't really understand what they're saying.
这首歌节奏很快，所以有时你不太明白他们在唱什么。
Personally, I did not know the lyrics of Jingle Bells until we started doing this podcast.
就我个人而言，直到我们开始做这个播客，我才知道《铃儿响叮当》的歌词。
Really?
真的吗？
Well, because when we sing it, we mumble.
嗯，因为我们唱的时候会含糊不清。
You know, you can't hear all the words.
你知道，你听不清所有词。
So jingle bells, jingle bells, you don't know the words, but dashing through the snow.
所以“铃儿响叮当，铃儿响叮当”，你不知道歌词，但“奔驰在雪地上”
Sometimes you have to just think of it very clearly.
有时候你得仔细想想。
Very good.
非常好。
So that's all the words we have for this podcast.
这就是我们这期播客的全部内容。
It's a very good Christmas carol.
这是一首很棒的圣诞颂歌。
It's very catchy and I don't know how old it is.
它很朗朗上口，我不知道它有多古老了。
I've heard it since I was small.
我从小就一直听。
Well probably old enough to come from a time when there weren't cars because there was
嗯，可能够古老，来自还没有汽车的时代，因为那时有
sleigh.
雪橇。
And when they used ore, because I don't see people use ore anymore.
而且他们用桨，因为现在我没见人用桨了。
No, I think it's mostly just songs and poems.
不，我觉得现在主要只是歌曲和诗歌里才有。
You see it a lot in the 19th century.
在19世纪经常能看到。
But it is interesting also, I guess, the relationship between the sleighs and snow.
但我觉得，雪橇和雪之间的关系也很有趣。
Christmas is always related to this, even though in some places you don't have snow
圣诞节总是和这个联系在一起，尽管有些地方
during Christmas.
圣诞节时没有雪。
That's right, but it does.
没错，但确实如此。
I mean, we're here in Shanghai and we can hear people singing this song, so.
我的意思是，我们在上海，还能听到人们唱这首歌，所以
And there's no snow.
而且这里没有雪。
So I think it's just a way to think about the season of Christmas and the attitude of
所以我觉得这只是一种方式来感受圣诞节的氛围和
people when it's Christmas time.
人们在圣诞节时的心情。
Right.
对。
So I hope you enjoyed our lesson.
所以希望你喜欢我们的课程。
If you have any questions about this Christmas carol, you can let us know on EnglishPod.com.
如果你对这首圣诞颂歌有任何疑问，可以在EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
And we'll also post the other verses, the less known verses of Jingle Bells because
我们还会发布《铃儿响叮当》的其他段落，那些不太知名的段落，因为
it's actually a pretty long song.
它其实是一首很长的歌。
Very long and I don't know any of the other verses to be honest with you.
很长，老实说，其他段落我一个都不知道。
Exactly.
没错。
We'll post the first one and the chorus because it's the most popular one.
我们会发布第一段和副歌，因为这是最流行的部分。
So we'll see you guys there and Merry Christmas!
那我们到时候见，圣诞快乐！
Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐！
Bye.
再见。